[{"Question": "Which of these will account for over 90% of Rio 2016's Olympic c.$4bn revenues?", "Options": ["Broadcast and Tickets", "Tickets and Fast Food", "Broadcast and Sponsorship", "Fast food and Sponsorship"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "Prior to Brazil (Rio 2016), how many southern hemisphere nations have hosted the Summer Olympics", "Options": [1.0, 2.0, 3.0, 4.0], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "How many athletes will India send to the 2016 Paralympics in Rio De Janeiro?", "Options": [16.0, 19.0, 20.0, 37.0], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Which country ranks number one in the 2016 Rio Olympics medal standings?", "Options": ["China", "Russia", "USA", "Germany"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "Who declared the the official closing of the 2016 Olympics?", "Options": ["Demetrius Vikelas", "Juan Antonio Samaranch", "Jacques Rogge", "Thomas Bach"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Identify the athlete who became the first Iranian woman to win an Olympic medal recently.", "Options": ["Mahsa Javar", "Najmeh Khedmati", "Leila Rajabi", "Kimia Alizadeh Zenoorin"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Which country won the gold medal in women's football event at the Rio Olympics?", "Options": ["Germany", "Great Britain", "France", "Sweden"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "Who won the men\u2019s 200m gold in the 2016 Rio Olympics?", "Options": ["Adam Gemili", "Michael Johnson", "Colin Jackson", "Usain Bolt"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Which nation has won its first gold medal in soccer in the 2016 Olympics?", "Options": ["Germany", "Brazil", "France", "China"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Who won the gold medal in the Men's 4 \u00d7 100 metres relay in the Rio Olympics?", "Options": ["Ryota Yamagata", "Mike Rodgers", "Usain Bolt", "Ricardo de Souza"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "Anita Wlodarczyk who created a world record of 82.29m in women\u2019s hammer throw to win gold at Rio Olympics belongs to which country?", "Options": ["Denmark", "Poland", "Russia", "Germany"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Who created a world record of 82.29m in women\u2019s hammer throw to win gold at Rio Olympics?", "Options": ["Anita Wlodarczyk", "Sophie Hitchon", "Wenxiu Zhang", "None of the above"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "Who won the gold medal in men\u2019s singles tennis category in Rio 2016 Olympic Games?", "Options": ["Noval Djokovic", "Rafael Nadal", "Andy Murray", "Juan Martin Del Potro"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Notes": "Darya Klishina has won her appeal to compete at the Rio Olympics. The Court of Arbitration for Sport ruled that she is eligible to take part. CAS has overruled a last minute ban imposed on her by the International Association of Athletics Federations (IAAF). Klishina was the only one of 68 Russians cleared to participate in Rio by the IAAF.", "Question": "Name the Russian track and field athlete who has won her appeal to compete at the Rio Olympics.", "Options": ["Olga Kharitonova", "Yelena Andreyeva", "Ekaterina Smirnova", "Darya Klishina"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Who of the following lit the 2016 Olympic cauldron?", "Options": ["Gustavo Kuerten", "Vanderlei de Lima", "Desiree Henry", "Irina Rodnina"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "The opening ceremony of 2016 Rio Olympics was held at which stadium?", "Options": ["Rice\u2013Eccles Stadium", "BC Place Stadium", "Maracana Stadium", "Turin Stadium"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "Who of the following became the first Brazilian to win a Gold medal at 2016 Rio Olympics?", "Options": ["Judoka Silva", "Erika Miranda", "Mayra Aguiar", "Mariana Silva"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "Which country won the gold in first-ever Olympic Women's Rugby Sevens Championship in Rio de Janeiro?", "Options": ["New Zealand", "Canada", "Britain", "Australia"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Name the swimmer who became the first swimmer to win four consecutive gold medals in same event?", "Options": ["Mark Spitz", "Matt Biondi", "Ryan Lochte", "Michael Phelps"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "Ma Long defeated China\u2019s Zhang Jike by 4-0 to win the gold medal in Table Tennis at Rio Olympics. With this win, Long also became the fifth male player to complete the Grand Slam. He belongs to which country?", "Options": ["China", "Japan", "South Korea", "Vietnam"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "How many sports are to be played in Rio Olympics?", "Options": [24.0, 26.0, 28.0, 30.0], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "The person, after whom the mascot name is given in Rio Olympics was famous as __________", "Options": ["Freedom fighter", "Athlete", "Social Worker", "Musician"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Question": "What is the name of the Mascot for Rio Olympics?", "Options": ["Wenlock", "Bely Mishka", "Vinicius", "Soohorang"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "Which of the following country is taking part in Summer Olympics for the first along with Kosovo?", "Options": ["North Sudan", "South Sudan", "East Sudan", "West Sudan"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "What is the motto of the Olympics, 2016?", "Options": ["Brotherhood of the world", "A New Beginning", "A New World", "Brotherhood of Men"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Question": "Which city came second in bidding for 31st Olympics (2016)?", "Options": ["Tokyo, Japan", "Madrid, Spain", "New York, USA", "Amsterdam, Netherlands"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "What is the number of participating countries in Rio Olympics 2016?", "Options": [192.0, 200.0, 204.0, 206.0], "Answers": "D"}, {"Notes": "Almaz Ayana is an Ethiopian female long-distance runner. On August 12 she smashed the World record to win the Olympic 10,000 metres title. Her time was 14 sec inside the 29:31.78 set by China's Wang Junxia in 1993. It was the first time in seven years that a female athlete had run 10,000m in under 30 minutes. Kenya\u2019s Vivian Cheruiyot had to settle for silver while Ethiopian Tirunesh Dibaba, the defending Olympic champion grabbed bronze.", "Question": "Almaz Ayana who was  in news during the Rio Olympics, is a ______.", "Options": ["Journalist", "Sportsperson", "Social activist", "Writer"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Notes": "China's Chen Xinyi has become the first swimmer to fail a doping test at the Rio Olympics. Chen Xinyi tested positive on August 7 for hydrochlorothiazide, a banned substance. She has already competed in the 100-meter butterfly event and placed fourth in the final. She rose to fame at the National Games in 2013. She won gold at the women's 100-meter butterfly at the 2014 Asian Games in Incheon.", "Question": "Name the swimmer who has become the first swimmer to fail a doping test at the Rio Olympics.", "Options": ["Chen Xinyi", "Zhang Linli", "Wang Junxia", "Le Jingyi"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Notes": "Russia's weightlifting team has been banned from competing at the Rio Olympics because of doping offences. Two of the eight-strong weightlifting team had already been banned for prior violations, and another four were named in the MccLaren report. Russia's Sports Minister said 272 of the original 387 athletes selected had been cleared to compete in Rio. The Games get under way on 5 August.", "Question": "Which country's weightlifting team has been banned from competing at the Rio Olympics because of doping offences?", "Options": ["China", "Russia", "USA", "Argentina"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Who won the first medal at Rio Olympics?", "Options": ["Mackenzie Brown", "Eva Lee", "Ginny Trasher", "Mikaela Mayer"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Notes": "The diving pool was the biggest talking point in Rio for a few days, in part because it took so long to figure out what made it turn green.\u00a0", "Question": "What caused the Olympic diving pool to turn green?", "Options": ["Insecticide", "Hydrogen Peroxide", "Algae", "Food Coloring"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Youngest athlete participated in Rio olympics 2016 is Meet Gaurika Singh. she represented Nepal. she is associated with of the following sport ?", "Options": ["Boxing", "Badminton", "Long Jump", "Swimming"], "Answers": "D"}, {"Notes": "South Pacific Nation of Tuvalu had only 1 athlete.", "Question": "Which is the Smallest Olympic Team of 2016 Rio Olympics?", "Options": ["Somalia", "Tuvalu", "Chad", "Bhutan"], "Answers": "B"}, {"Question": "Which countriy who won their first-ever medal at Olympics at Rio?", "Options": ["Bhutan", "Somalia", "Fiji", "Sudan"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Notes": "RenQian : 15-Year Old won gold medal in  Women\u2019s 10m Platform Diving Event.", "Question": "Who is the youngest athlete to win Gold Medal at Rio?", "Options": ["RenQian", "Tara Lipinsk", "Gaurika Singh", "Inge Sorensen"], "Answers": "A"}, {"Question": "Which of the following rowing events taking place at the 2016 Olympic Games does not feature women?\u00a0", "Options": ["Quadruple Sculls", "Single Sculls", "Coxless Four", "Coxless Pair"], "Answers": "C"}, {"Notes": "Vinicius and Tom are the official mascots of 2016 olympics.", "Question": "How many\u00a0official\u00a0mascots\u00a0will the 2016 games have?\u00a0", "Options": [1.0, 2.0, 3.0, 4.0], "Answers": "B"}]